Guide to the Robert J. Corry Papers, 1953-2001 UA.90.F59
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Books and Chapters, II.
  - Draft: Techniques and Experience of pancreatic transplantation (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Draft: Transplantation and blood transfusion, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Draft: Simultaneous Pancreas-Kidney transplantation (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Draft: Pregnancy after pancreatic transplantation (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Draft (unpublished?): Effect of Ischemic injury on acute rejection, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 104)
- Talks, III.
  This series contains documents which relate to various talks given by Corry to a variety of professional, student, international, and community groups. Items are arranged chronologically. The materials representing each talk may include speech notes, drafts, eventual publications of the remarks, and visual aid materials.
  - Effect of blood transfusions on survival of cadaver and living related renal transplants, ASTS, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - ACT talk: diffusion of technology regarding the delivery of transplantation ser ices, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Critical analysis of mortality and graft loss, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Diffusion of technology regarding the delivery of transplantation services, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Public policy and organ distribution, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Donor-specific transfusion v. cyclosporine therapy, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Recommendations regarding issues facing organ transplantation, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Impact of recent federal legislation on transplantation, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Statement of ATS before subcommittee on health and environment, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Third "revised" talks for submission to ASTS membership, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - ASTS Presidential address, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - ASTS Presidential address, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Summation address - pancreatic transplantation, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Preoperative transfusions, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Function of pancreas allografts, Western surgical association, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Speech for AAMC, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Prolongation of allograft and xenograft survival, RJC Tx society international, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Heath care technology in the teaching hospital, hospital and health administration symposium, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Comments on personal vision for the coming year, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Throchmorton surgical society, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Transfusions in transplantation, British TX society, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Recent advances in pancreatic transplantation, Wolkoff Memorial lecture, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - American transplantation, northeast Ohio tx society, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Distribution of medical technology, Iowa Leadership program, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Third Spitzingsee meeting, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - PS Russell festschrift event, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - University of Toronto: Day in transplantation, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - International congress transplantation society, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - NFK, CAL Diner honoring Oscar Salvatierra, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Testimonial dinner speech for Oscar Salvatierra, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Teleconference on organ donation, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Second international congress Middle Eastern society for organ transplantation, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Evolving state of the national organ procurement...network, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Talk for Hospital and Health administration students, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Second international meeting on organization aspects of transplantation, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Committee meeting, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Quality of life following pancreatic transplantation, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Fourth international congress on pancreas and islet transplantation, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Transplantation council presentation, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Fifth congress of the international pancreas and islet Transplantation association, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - CORE meeting, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Pancreatic transplantation, St. Francis, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Italian transplant program, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Outreach program lecture, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Second annual conference on Immunosuppression, letter, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Central surgical association, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Pancreas controversies session, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - XIX International congress of transplantation society abstract and article, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - United Network for Organ Sharing, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Talk, unknown, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Organ Allocation Talk, Milan, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Research, IV.
  This series includes materials relevant to research in which Robert Corry participated. Information includes meeting notes, funding information, relevant articles, results, procedures, and other notes. Materials are roughly arranged by research subject.
  - 15-Deoxysperagualin, 1975-1987 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Deoxyspergualion funding and Tokyo visit, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Deoxysperagualin research and correspondence, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Meeting c. Nippon Kayaku and Bristol-Myers re 15-deoxy, Chicago, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Deoxysperagualin studies, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Bristol Myers-Squibb company, concerning deoysperagulin, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Deoxysperagualin meeting (Bristol-Myers), 1990 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Deoxysperagualin funding, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Hypertology of Rat Kidneys - data and reports, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Renal Hypertology study references, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Rat kidney hypertology, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Pancreas Renal transplant research report, 1984-85 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - FK506 trial research analysis, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Surgical risk paper by Gruessner, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Proliferation of transplant programs, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Lab animal procedures, permissions, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Animal application for research, university of Pittsburgh, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Research correspondence and articles, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Research folder, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Lab progress report, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Fujisawa Pharmaceutical Co., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Interleukin-2 production, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Grants, V.
  This series contains materials which relate to grants for which Corry applied or received funding. Materials include draft proposals, submitted proposals, result reports, and meeting notes. Materials are arranged in a roughly chronological order: however, not all materials are dated.
  - Grant award: mechanism of transfusion in improving allograft survival, National institute of arthritis, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Splenic-induced tolerance: juvenile diabetes foundation, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Splenic-induced tolerance: juvenile diabetes foundation, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Characterization of transfusion-induced suppressor cells, DHHS, 1984-86 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Characterization of SCA DST, 1989-90 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Grant application: immuno suppression by en bloc, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Grant: Immunosupression by En-Bloc spleen-pancreas, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Grant: Hunsicker clinical trials, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Grant application - combined bone marrow and organ transplantation in humans, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Grant application JDFI - John Fung's contribution, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - JDM Grants, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Professional Activities, VI.
  This series contains a wide variety of materials, all of which relate to the professional development and visibility of Robert Corry. This includes article review commentaries, articles read by Corry to keep current in the field, membership in professional associations, newspaper articles about Corry and transplantation programs in Iowa and Pittsburgh, and related meetings and correspondence.
  - Chimerism articles, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chimerism articles, 1992-94 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Chimerism lab paper, revised, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Neomorphics: Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Neomorphics: Articles, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Neomorphics: Meetings, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - FK506 (drug use), 1994 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Photopheresis articles, 1988-92 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Pancreas Tx articles, 1989-94 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Parathyroid tx, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Parathyroid paper, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Immunology articles (not by Corry), undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Bill Bean articles, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Transplantation and communications consensus report, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Surgical Risk" Review, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Fed Legis Review, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Clin. Transplantation Review, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Appendicitis Review, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Starzl Paper for review, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Heath care technology, HHA symposium, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Other articles for review, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Treatment Strategies Review, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - International pancreas transplant registry, advisory committee invite, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - UNOS update newsletter, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - UNOS: Membership committee, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - UNOS kidney-pancreas transplantation committee meetings, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
  - UNOS: Surgical requirements, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Pancreas allocation: UNOS, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - UNOS Database, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - UNOS Letter, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - UNOS equitable organ allocation statement, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - UNOS council for organ availability, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - UNOS: New transplant laws, Hunsicker correspondence, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - ASTS membership application, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - ASTS abstracts for review, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - AAMC compensation for faculty, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - ASA, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - ASA Discussion, Bartlet papers, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Article about Corry, in German, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - ASA correspondence, articles, etc., 1967-99 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Organ shortage presentation, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - CORE Organ donor information 1994-95 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - CORE Letter re procurement statistics, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Abstracts, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 05-07)
  - Halstead society, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Behring institute, 1985-86 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cyclo workshop, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - VGJS Journal, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - First international symposium on hereditary pancreatitus, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - TS today newsletter, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - TS Ballot, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - PTI Newsletter, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - IPTR newsletters, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Pacemaker newsletter: University of Iowa, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Spectation, University of Iowa newspaper special feature on surgery, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Misc. newsletters, 1996-97 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper articles and editorials: UIHC v. Des Moines hospitals, newspaper clippings, 1986-7 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Cedar Rapids Gazette series on transplantation, clippings, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, Articles, undated (Box 5, Folder 22-24)
- Administrative, VII.
  This series contains information used by Corry during the course of his professional activities. This material includes correspondence, procedures and protocols, departmental organization information and reviews, patient information, surgery reports, and personal information such as Corry's CV and photographs related to professional organizations.
  To protect the privacy of individuals, some files in Boxes 5, 6 and 7 are restricted. For questions about conditions of access, contact the University Archivist.
  - Proposal for restructuring pancreas transplant program, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Surgery departmental review, 1982-89 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Clarification of Donor status, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Transplant resource guide for patients and families, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Pitt recovery technique, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Pancreas exclusion criteria, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Logistics and technique for procurement of...from same donor, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Liver-pancreas retrieval technique, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Kauffman paper on the pancreas, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Halifax immuno-suppression protocol, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Protocols, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Pretreatment protocol data (pretreated v. non-pretreated), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Editorial Board: PGS, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Continuing education, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - University of Minnesota, "pancreas poor results" correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 40-47)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    RESTRICTED
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 01-04)
  - Colloston transplantation correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Pitkin Letter, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Jordan Letter, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Flory Letter, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Colloston Letter, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letter re. Appointment to Pitt, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Thomas Detre, M.D., correspondence concerning patient, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letter form BQCT, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Innocenti correspondence, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Transplant correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 14-17)
  - Blood viscosity, correspondence and article, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Iowa PAWI, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Legal case, Barrett v. JHH, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Paul Russel - mouse microsurgery correspondence and articles, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Financial clearance, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Local patient info, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - State transplantation profiles (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Corry CV, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Massachusetts general hospital surgery experience, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Staff photo, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Personal, 1996-97 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - RJC: VAMC Op Reports, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - RJC: Transplant Op and Path Reports, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Operation notes, Arterial Fistula, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Surgery Reports (Box 6, Folder 32-33)
  - History of University of Iowa Transplantation service, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Pancreas Articles for talks and presentations, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Transplant notebook, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Assistant in Surgery appointment, Mass. General Hospital, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Education, VIII.
  These records come from Corry's undergraduate career at Yale University between 1953 and 1957. They include notes, syllabi, tests, and assignments from classes he attended.
  - Sociology Syllabus, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - History of East Asian Civilizations course, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - History 39 graded assignments, 1956-57 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Culture and Behavior, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Psychology notes and test, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 07-08)
  - English, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - High school Latin notes, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Geometry Assignments, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - English assignments, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - World history notes and assignments, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Spanish notes and assignments, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - English essays, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Biology, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Chemistry notes, lab reports, tests, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Anthropology, physics notebooks, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 18-19)
  - English 56 notebook, 1956-57 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - CoB92, notebook II, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - History 23b notebook, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Media, IX.
  This series contains various slides, transparencies, and photographs which were likely used by Corry for presentations, talks, and educational activities.
  - Photographs (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Strategic Plan slides for presentation, Iowa scenes slides, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Photograph, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Transparencies (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Slides (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Slide Creation material (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Pancreaticoduodenal Transplantation presentation slides, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Visual Aid creation material (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Photographs (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Banner (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Poster sections (Box 8, Folder 2)